all right guys the moment everyone has
been waiting for introducing my glute
Lab Fort Lauderdale here's my favorite
thing about my gym whenever I move to a
different city this happened in San
Diego and now it's happened in Fort
ludell Miami area this isn't to just say
everyone copies me I think a lot of gym
owners aren't familiar with good glute
training equipment so when I move to the
area and I get all of the influencers to
start training with me all the gym
owners follow those influencers and
those lifters and they get exposed to
all this amazing equipment they've never
seen before so just being familiarized
with the equipment and then knowing you
got to stay competitive you got to get
good glute train equipment cuz the women
are speaking their minds the Bros get
all their quad and hamstring and pec and
delt and back in our machines women are
speaking their minds they're saying look
we want glute equipment and so in San
Diego and Florida the glute machines
have exploded seriously every gym now
has a hip thrust machine abduction
machines I'm seeing BC strength
equipment everywhere I'm seeing booty
Builder and glute Builder equipment
everywhere now so I'm very excited to
show off my gym come on
in all right guys currently there are
six Bays all right Bay one is the hip
thrust room all right this is the BC
strength Thruster Pro this is the best
plate loaded Thruster on the market in
my opinion most people will agree I'm
going to explain how I came up with this
but yeah the BC strength Thruster Pro
this gets used actually the second most
here what gets used the most is Thruster
3.0 with the rotisserie or the rotary
attachment this is the squad favorite
all my girls in Fort Lauderdale are
doing this it's their favorite thing to
thrust off of interestingly this is the
Thruster 2.0 and it is not as popular my
San Diego Squad like here's Carly this
is Carly hip dusting
765 back in 2020 they all learned off
the 2.0 the standard way to hip thrust
but all the girls here like the 3.0 with
the rotary attachment they love the
rotating backpad I don't like this I
only use the Thruster Pro but they love
this so we've got the Thruster Pro we've
got the scorcher now this scorcher was
my very first invention so this is not
sold anymore sorex made this for me this
is from 2006 this is my very first hip
thrust invention this is very similar to
the device on my patent that I applied
for back in 2006 so yeah this here is
the very first hip thrust apparatus ever
made well this isn't the exact one I had
sorex remake it for me but we stopped
selling it because it's a very clunky
piece of equipment but let me tell you
back in the day my girls did three
different types of hip thrust outfit
they did single leg where they use the
handles and I would still say this is
the very best way to do single leg hip
thrust you're so stable but you can go
so deep and have so much range of motion
so for single leg it's the best but we
also did band with these guys we take
the handles off we do band hip thrust
and barbell hip thrust but the barbell
hip thrust were complicated because we
had to have someone on each side so you
had to have two trainers two spotters
pick the weight up the client would
slide underneath set the weight on their
lap they do their set and then we'd hold
the weight they'd slide out and then we
drop it from 200 6 to 2008 that's the
way we hip thrusted we never used a
standard bench I didn't come up with a
standard bench method until I was
writing my ebook and I wanted to show
the masses how to hip that came in 2009
at my first gym lifts it was in
Scottdale and gy Ranch uh from like I
said 2006 to 2008 everyone hip thrusted
off of the scorcher I call this the
scorcher with a K this was the first
exercise that everyone did when they
came in they'd use the scorcher they do
either band single legegg or barbell and
then they move on to their other
exercises okay moving along this is not
a hip thrust device this is an old
school Hammer Strength unit but I
actually modified this okay so this is
their hip and glute machine and I'm
going to show you the Rogers unit they
improved upon it right here however I
modified this so that it only goes down
to about right there so you can't get
full hip extension but look at the
torque look at this giant lever arm this
is hardest in the bottom position okay
okay so you slide Bight in it and it's
this crazy amount of torque in deep hip
flexion so we use this to strengthen
glute strength in deep hip flexion in my
opinion there's nothing better than this
well arguably you could say like a a
reverse lunge the problem is think of
like the bottom of a leg press some
people get lower back pain because they
Butt Wink well this is like that on
steroids because probably one out of two
one out of three people maybe love it
they're like this is one of my favorite
glute machines and the other one out of
two or like two out of three they just
feel all in their low back and they're
and they'd probably get injured if I had
them keep doing it so I never
manufactured it I thought it was a great
idea I keep it here I do it myself
sometimes I have a few clients that do
it but this doesn't get used that much
just because it irritates some people's
low back some people say make shoulder
pads make a belt do it one leg at a time
I tried it one leg at time I don't like
it but in theory this was going to be
the greatest glute exercise for working
that deep stretch position and it works
well but there are flaws with it so we
didn't move forward with the production
of it like I said it was a hammer strin
I elevated this we don't use this this
was their old lever arm it was easiest
at the bottom position the hardest at
full lockout we made this whole new
lever arm such that it would reverse the
torque angle curve and make it hardest
in the stretch easiest at the lockout
all right this is actually the Hammer
Strength uh glute drive and this is what
I use to make the be BC strength
prototype so if you look here this is
their old foot plate all I did was make
the foot plate a lot bigger and this way
it's closer to the back pad so it
accommodates shorter individuals I have
two clients here that are 410 and it
works fine for them I'm 6'4 I put my
feet in the middle this would work for
people who are even probably 7 ft tall
so Hammer Strength almost nailed it they
almost made the perfect device they had
two flaws number one they needed a
bigger foot plate and number two their
plate pegs only come out to about right
here you can only put four plates on
that would be the hip thrust is like a
leg press you can use a lot of plates so
that would be like having a leg press
machine with a plate peg this big
everyone would be frustrated so people
who buy the Hammer Strength are pissed
they're like why can I only load four
plates on so we made the plate pad way
longer and you can actually fit 10
plates on here we've never had anyone do
10 plates but I have had a couple strong
Bros in here do 8 to n plates for low
wraps that's what I and we used this in
my Las Vegas house for like 2 years and
everyone loved it and then eventually we
made the BC strength Thruster Pro but
this was the first prototype for it
moving on this is the body Master's low
back machine okay now if you look at
this they say it's low back but check
this out that's a hip thrust turn that
aside and that's a hip thrust okay
that's bent leg hip extension so I did
this back in the late '90s and early
2000s I was using this machine and I was
like man this is actually a glute
machine this is hip extension this is
not back extension this is hip extension
but the problem is if you're a big guy
like I could do the stack for some reps
but this is what you put your feet
against it only comes to right here and
yeah if you're wide like if you're big
like me my legs slide off of it but it
was an awesome unit I had it here and I
was actually overloading the negative
cuz I could push on this and have
enhanced Ecentric you know bent leg hip
extensions back in the day when I first
opened glute I was using this a ton
however my friend Arturo he's the owner
of glute Builder equipment he made it
even better so that's right here I'm
going to show you that in a second but
first I'm going to show you the glute
Builder glute drive or glute Builder hip
thrust okay so Arturo made this this
unit is really Innovative okay cuz it
has the shoulder harness so you can push
back against it it also look at the foot
plate it's angled out so that you
naturally externally rotate and it's
like a moving Smith machine it moves
vertically and horizontally a lot of my
girls love this but this is what's so
funny about women hip thrusts are the
female equivalent of the bench press let
me explain with bench press Bros get so
pissed like if they have a unit that
they can only load like one plate on
each side and it's less than what they
bench with a barbell this is really hard
to hip thrust off of like three plates
like I use three and four plates per
side but on like the Hammer Strength or
the Nautilus scw driver or the BC
strength I might use five or six plates
a lot of my clients will be like I mean
I like like this but how come it's so
hard how come I can only do two plates
on it and I'm like who cares does it
work your glutes you feel it like in
your glutes yes I do but they like
moving weight and it's like hilarious in
general women don't care about weight as
much as men do but they do what they hip
thrust they want to move some serious
load and that cracks me up but they like
the glute Builder but I would still say
that the BC strength Thruster Pro they
like a little bit more so I would say
the Thruster Pro is the best plate
loaded device follow by Hammer Strength
and then probably you've got this glute
Builder unit there's a a booty Builder
plate loaded unit there's several others
but where glute Builder did nail it
though is with this device this is their
kneeling glute isolator and this is just
like the body Masters but significantly
improved upon so what Arturo did he made
this longer he made this pad rounded he
made the range of motion go a little
deeper and he made the lever arm so
that's really heavy at the bottom but
you can also attach bands and overload
the lock out so when you get in here and
do this it feels just like a hip thrust
it's bent leg hip extension except
you're not using your quads so it takes
the quads out of it so all you feel on
this is like you feel mostly glutes you
might feel a little bit of adductors and
hammies but yeah this is an awesome
glute machine there's a learning curve
to it but my girls love it I like using
bands on it and really emphasizing The
Squeeze because I will use this unit for
the stretch position this is the Rogers
pendulum reverse glute ham now there's a
learning curve to this too this is this
giant machine it's annoying cuz if you
want to order these they're like I don't
know at least 6 months backed up it
might even be longer now it's this giant
machine they make equipment for athletes
however what we do is you got to put a
lot of padding on the thing about this
whole room is you always need padding
here like on each one of the devices you
need padding to keep your hips in place
or to move the bar for hip thrust so you
need more padding than what this
provides my girls get really strong at
these and we put an extra padding just
like we use for everything you can't
just use the belt on these guys in fact
some of my girls will even double up
they'll use extra padding on the belt
and even more padding than that when you
got women thrusting five six plates per
side they tend to bruise they can get
scrapes so we're all about the padding
here anyway we use extra padding but a
lot of times here we we just do the
bottom position we just to length and
partials to work the stretch you can do
this for a full range of motion but we
load it up extra heavy and just work the
stretch position the only problem with
that is you need a spotter to help you
rack the weight the last thing I want to
talk about here is the standing booty
Builder the standing hip thrust I don't
like it that much some of my girls like
it but it's nice because sometimes it's
just nice when you're bored and sick of
hip thrust you can do this instead it
was genius in design but it just doesn't
feel quite as good as normal hip thrust
nevertheless a lot of people like it I
do want to mention our PR Bell
okay I have this in San Diego I have
this in Florida whenever a PR is set
someone will say ring that
hell and It Centers people on setting
PRS on gaining strength so if you're a
gym owner you should have a PR bell too
okay so I also have all my bands here
here's all of our glute Loops these are
mostly all BC strength bands but yeah
what I love about hip dust is you can
add load to the lockout if you want
because you can hip dust three times a
week sometimes you want to emphasize the
lockout even more when you come into
glute lab if you're new here all right
and it's your first time here I'll say
to make it easy do one thing in this
room cuz this is the hip thrust room do
one thing in that room cuz that's the
quad or like squat lunge room do one
thing in this room cuz this is the
hamstring or like the hinge or leg curl
room and then do two things in this room
because this is the kickback an
abduction room so now I'm going to take
you through our Kickback and abduction
equipment so the first thing I'm going
to show you is this glute Builder
Kickback this is my favorite Kickback it
moves you through such a large range of
motion it's amazing yeah Arturo nailis
it's my favorite Kickback machine can't
say enough about this unit the women
love it so if you're a gym owner looking
for a good Kickback machine glute
Builder is the favorite next up we've
got the snow angel machine everyone
wants to know the brand I don't even
remember the Brand This is fedal here's
the deal they modeled the Hammer
Strength but they made it way too big
this is tall enough like I'm 6'4 this is
tall enough for like a freaking 7f
footer yeah this is so big yeah so they
made this so tall for someone like giant
they made this for Giants well this
works out in our favor because we don't
well some of my girls will do it upright
but we actually use it for laying back
so here's what we do we lay back and
it's like basically
frontal plane hip abduction now okay now
it's frontal plane you're working the
glute medius it's brilliant for that we
add yoga blocks here so that your feet
touch for more active range of motion I
would say this is my favorite glute
medius machine it's hit or miss with the
girls most of them love it but some
don't some prefer the other machines
which I will show you okay now we've got
the free motion now I use this for delt
work you can use it for upper body work
obviously you can do all the kickback
you know and standing abduction you can
do kneeling there's a bunch of different
types of Kickbacks off of here with the
Kickbacks we tend to use the BC strength
strap just makes things easier all right
moving on here we have the seated hip
abduction machine now this is the Life
Fitness this is the same one I have in
Vegas and it's not as good as my sbck
from San Diego my San Diego unit is the
best ever this one doesn't start till
here so we always put pads or blocks in
between our legs but we do two distinct
types of abduction we do leaning forward
and we do bridged when you do bridged
you're working the glute medius when you
lean for forward a lot you're working
more glutitis Maximus this is a staple
every gym should have one of these now
this is the Glu I wish I invented this
people ask me if I invented this I say
no it's so genius though the only thing
we do differently we do this differently
than other gyms cuz they will lay back
and they will do it just like this they
will go like this sit against it like
that okay now we will put pads here I
want knees touching together and I want
knees touching the chest so what we do
is we will put our feet up high and lean
forward like this so knees to chest and
knees touching so you want your knees
come up as high as possible when you do
it like this this is simultaneous hip
extension and hip abduction but check
out the angle it's more I would say it's
more hip extension than hip abduction
when you do it like this this is a
length and partial for the glut the
thing is this is why it's so genius when
you're in really deep hip flexion okay
when you are way down deep you're
stretching the glutes but the glutes
don't activate well the reason why they
don't activate well is because the
adductor Magnus has a better moment arm
it has better leverage in very deep hip
flexion well when you produce abduction
at the same time I think it would take a
little bit of the adductor out of it and
focus more on the glutes so it's a
length and partial stretch position work
for the glutes but it's even more
effective because it's going to take
some adductor out of it and focus more
on the glutes it's genius we have all
these protocols we do off this but I
think this is such an awesome glute
machine it's hard to find every good
glute gym should have a gluteator now we
have the max pump 3D abductor they made
this and then they quit making it and
it's so awesome it's a lot like the Glu
the only thing is if you look at the
direction it's a little bit more
abduction and a little bit less hip
extension I love these I actually sit
straight up into them and it really
works the stretch position too so I have
this in San Diego as well the girls love
it and then finally we have the glute
Builder 3D abductor and what I love
about this is the seat moves so you can
go all the way down so when you do it
from here and you do abduction this way
okay it's mostly glute medius it's upper
glutes about half of my girls like it
this way and half of the girls Bridge up
on it and they do it bridged but they
love this machine but you can also move
the seat forward you really don't have
to move the seat though you could just
lean forward but if you wanted to the
seat goes up to right here you could
lean forward even more than this if you
wanted and then we have the Hammer
Strength multi-hit machine we do two
different types of Kickbacks off this we
do length and partial Kickbacks where
way we go way up high okay I have to put
this down for me but you get that leg
really high up and here you have to load
up really heavy you have to load up like
the whole stack you have to pin weight
to the stack and you just do this range
and you're working that glute in the
Deep stretch we don't bother locking out
cuz it gets weird when you're focused up
here and then you come all the way down
it rolls up too high on the thigh so we
only do the lengthen position but then
we will also kind of go to here and just
focus more on the squeeze like this so
we do two types of Kickbacks we also do
abduction like this it takes some
getting used to cuz you're angled this
way but that works the glute medius very
well and then we've got all of our
benches here we have the glute slide
this is like a band loaded device okay
and you can do different abduction
exercises off of it and you can make it
really really hard to do you can also do
different Kickbacks off of it I like
this for athletes especially because it
gets you winded when you use this we've
got the tripod graveyard this is how you
know it's an influencer gym here we've
got the infamous this power pole this
lets you do standing hip thrust it's
amazing but everyone thinks that I'm
either a biomechanical [__] or just
posting for clickbait cuz if you have a
pretty woman do this it'll get millions
of views and then people will be like
what a stupid device it's actually
amazing I wish I invented it this was
invented by Chuck vapol a badass
powerlifter from Westside under Louis
Simmons and my girls like kneeling hip
thrust I like standing but oh my God the
lockout is hard it's amazing finally we
have all of our pads all of our wedges
all of our mats all of our sponges here
we have all of our ankle weights our BC
strength ankle weights you know the BC
strength sponges um all the different
pads because a good glute gym should
have tons of accessories tons of them
glute Loops bands sponges pads mats and
you got to replace these regularly cuz
they don't last and that's where I'm
going man some of these gyms are making
so much profit and they don't buy buy
any of these special pieces that really
help you train more effectively and like
just invest a couple hundred bucks a
month just know that you're going to
have to spend a couple hundred bucks a
month to replace these things the ladies
are going to appreciate it because it
makes their glute training more
effective so yeah if you're a gym owner
expect to have to keep up with these
glot training specialty um accessory
fees But ultimately it'll make you stand
out from the competition and retain and
build new members all right here we've
got Masa masa's probably my my best
friend Masa or Brad shenfeld or my two
best friends yeah this is Masa akber May
Persian she's um made it to the Arnold
um in my opinion she should have been in
the Olympia maybe she will one day but
she's a badass bikini competitor and I
think it was because of her that I just
blew up in like 2018 I started training
her in San Diego and everyone wanted to
be like Masa and she helped me get so
many bikini comp all of a sudden St I'm
training like 30 bikini competitors
because of her so she lives in Miami now
she comes and train here um but I also
have my quotes So on this mural of Carly
the thrust is a must that's one of my
popular quotes I got three popular
quotes Okay the second is abs are made
in the kitchen but glutes are made in
the gym I said that um when I was
filming for my promo for strong curves I
said it I was like wo and then finally
we have bathroom number one we actually
have five bathrooms in here we went over
overboard on the bathrooms so remember
for beginners it makes so convenient the
way this is set up because I say do one
thing in the hip thrust room one thing
in the squat lunge room one thing in the
hinge pull room and two things in the
abduction Kickback room and it's a
perfect workout makes things so simple
if they follow that it ensures that
they're going to develop the upper and
lower glutes they're also going to
develop the quads the hams and the
adductors so it's such a brilliant
system that is a system I came up with
like over 15 years ago and I've been
using it ever since I'm very proud to
have the very first glute gy the very
first glute Squad I had the first yeah
the first glute lab the glute lab was
the very first glute gym ever made I'm
very proud that I started the first kind
of like glute train equipment with the
scorcher and like the bench of the hip
Thruster then we started making the
glute Loop the t-bell um that were kind
of like other people's ideas but like
then people ran with it now you have
booty Builder and glute Builder really
specialized in glute training equipment
too and they're doing what I'm trying to
do build your own line of equipment so
that gyms can buy five pieces of of
glute training equipment I really
recommend booty Builder glute builder
for this purpose they're ahead of the
curve and now how nice is it for the
women Bros have always had all their
machines for their arms their delts
their lats their pecs even their quads
and hammies and calves even and a gym
will have all these pieces for every
single body part except glutes and now
because of BC strength and booty Builder
and glute Builder now you can have
stations you know glute stations you can
buy six pieces of equipment and be fully
loaded so that the women are happy too
and a lot of times women are 50% of the
gym membership but it's a male gym owner
and they don't care about women which is
annoying cuz women speak up say we want
the BC strength Thruster Pro and if they
don't Su it say just keep pounding them
and saying This is BS eventually on
someone in the neighborhood will build
another gym better glued equipment and
you can leave and never look back
because it's not fair that they have a
million pieces of equipment for men with
nothing for glutes for the ladies and
the men should be doing glutes too okay
now let's move on to the quad room here
we've got the Cybex hack squat this is
my favorite hack squat it's harder it's
more vertical like I have a hack squat
in San Diego that's less vertical and I
can go way heavier on it but yeah four
plates here is really hard four plates
is just as hard as five plates per side
San Diego all right now we've got the
Titan plate loaded leg press machine
obviously this is a lot cheaper than
like a sectorized leg extension machine
but I'm okay with keeping it why because
done this way it's going to work the
shorten position so here there's not
much torque here there's all the torque
right so you can work the quads in a
shorten position if you wanted to work
the quads in a lengthened position then
you could put this here okay and now
there's a lot of torque and now you come
up and then the torque reduces so it's
more torque in the stretch less torque
in the squeeze but you need a trainer or
a lifting partner to be able to do that
but you can also do seated leg curls in
a similar fashion I don't like the SE
leg curl version that much yeah a lot of
people are looking for cheaper ways to
do leg extensions this Titan unit is
good for that this is the Body Solid I
call it the lever squat the plate loaded
squat or lunge we did two things number
one we took off this piece in here
there's just a metal sheet when people
do lunges they bang their knee on the
metal so we just removed it all together
but the other thing we did you can see
these holes we redrilled the holes so
you could go deeper the original holes
were here so if I wanted to do squats on
this original Body Solid it's crazy cuz
this is my favorite place loaded squat
but the way they had it it was my least
favorite because if I was here here's
where it would touch right there okay
right here it would touch so I could
just squat to right here but what if
you're 5T tall if you're like a woman
that's like this tall they would squat
down to here and just do like a little
partial they couldn't use full range at
all because the crash bars were set so
high so we redrill the holes it's really
hard to do this I did this in San Diego
and I did it here and now you can go
deep the good news is that that we're
working on this same type of unit for BC
strength so we will be selling a unit
like this soon that's a little bit
better okay obviously we have squat
stands this is a rogue I do like the BC
strength a little bit more I'll show you
that in a minute we have a vertical
Smith machine this is Nautilus old
school I like vertical more for squats
and lunges I like the angled Smith
machines more for hip thrust and glute
Bridges and frog pump for hip thrust you
put your head here and you thrust this
way for frog pumps and glute Bridges you
put your head here and you pump this way
so you set up on different sides
depending on which exercise you're doing
now we have the seated hip adduction
machine this is mostly for me I love
having big adductors you also have the
gym pin here because I can do the stack
for 70 reps here so this lets you load
on extra plates I have two 100 lb plates
but yeah I have freaking she strong
adductors this is mostly for me I do
have a couple of girls who like doing it
I should mention also here next to the
Smith machine we always have our aerobic
step and risers for step UPS things like
that usually we have BC block which I'll
show you in that room we also have the
BC strength box squat box and this is
nice because you can go 12 in you can go
14 in you can go 16 in so suits people
from all Heights with box squats if I'm
doing Sumo box squats where I sit way
back I do 16 but if I have a short
shorter woman she'd do 12 we have the
Titan um single legegg squat stand here
this is great for Bulgarian split squats
it's a staple everyone should have a
Bulgarian split squat stand sorin x with
the the very first to make it back in
the day they made it 20 years ago I bet
now you can find it other places but
this is the booty Builder V squat you
can do V squats this way and face this
way I don't have a single client that
does that though why because this is a
glute gym my girls want glutes so they
face this way if you sit in this way and
face forward you're building the quads
it's really really hard for the quads
but if you face this way glutes and you
can do squats you can do good mornings
but the most brutal exercise is a single
leg squat standing here on one leg and
sit back such crazy amounts of torque in
the stretch position we love it all
right now we have the technogen leg
press in my Vegas and San Diego
locations I have the old school sbck
squat press that's my favorite leg press
but I kind of this is tied for my
favorite leg press what I like about is
you can go hole one to Hole 10 most of
my girls use hole one and they put this
pad here and this lets them go deeper
and they do leg press if if they're
trying to work quads they put their feet
lower if they're trying to work glutes
they put their feet higher but we do
lots of single leg and double leg leg
press off here for myself I use this I
do quad dominant deep leg presses I do
glute dominant leg presses I do single
leg leg presses but I also do partials
so I I also have my records that that I
have off hole three and then off of
whole five and then I also do band leg
presses I actually put a BC strength
band around here and around here and I
wedge it in here and it just makes the
lock out so much harder I would say
that's the most brutal thing we one of
the most brutal things we do here is the
banded leg presses so hard and then
finally the last thing in this in the
quad and squat room is the Atlantis
pendulum squat this is so much quad I
would probably say the hack squat is the
best quad Builder and then the pendulum
squat is a close second some people
would say this is best but this is so
much quads some girls who put their feet
up higher feel it in their glutes some
girls feel hack squats a lot in their
glutes I feel this all in my quads
though but yeah this is such a legendary
quad machine interesting a lot of the
ladies love it they love this more than
the hack squat a lot of them do this and
it feels good on their knees I do want
to show off the BC strength plates and
plate rack so this yeah this is a BC
strength plate rack and these BC
strength plates are so convenient how
nice it you just grip them they are a
little more expensive but every gym
owner that buys these they tell me Brett
I love your plates so much nicer than
having you know the metal plates that
are rust and they just are hard to
maneuver even cleaning up is so much
easier with these plates when you're
cleaning up people's plates you just
grab the handle slide them in okay I've
also got a lot of belts a lot of
different bands and gizmos we've got
bathroom number two and three
here and we've got Brett's mini fridge
where I have my diet ginger ale some
energy drinks my yogurts my peanut
butter bars okay now let's move on to
the hamstring room first off I want to
show you the mural this is Ashley Hodge
this is her first time pulling 405 it
was New Year's 2020 I flew in from Vegas
late on New Year's night and we met up
before midnight to deadlift and this is
look how happy she is so now she's going
to probably pull like 440 her in her
next competition hopefully now she can
triple this with a stiff bar this is a
deadlift bar you can see which bends
which makes a little bit easy easier now
this is my most popular quote of all
time if you think lifting weights is
dangerous try being weak being weak is
dangerous it's funny cuz you can Google
that and you see all kinds of people
claiming it at their own quote and I
said that for a teenan article in I
believe 2011 but this is probably my
most popular quote of all time I didn't
realize it would take off like that but
yeah people loved it sometimes you just
say something and takes off this is our
deadlift platform if you want people to
take squats seriously you got to have
squat stands or or a power rack if you
want people to take deadlift seriously
you need a deadlift station where the
bar is loaded you've got your deadlift
lever to help with racking and unracking
weights and you need a chalk bin next to
it so that they can chalk up their hands
and you need lots of plates nearby you
do these things and it makes deadlifting
so much more convenient here in the
hamstring room I've got the BC strength
hammy track and roller SX is the first
one to make this guy they called it the
glute ham roller I take partial credit
for this because I was telling me you
guys got to use rollerblade wheels for
my scorcher and brt saurin he's now the
owner of SX and he's like no Brett the
rollerblade wheels are too hard we'll
just get plastic Wheels I go B that's a
deal breaker you need rollerblade Wheels
it makes them so much nicer and know
last forever and it makes the rolling so
smooth so he sourced them and then he's
like Brett the you're right these
rollerblade wheels are amazing they
started putting these on everything and
it made him come up with the idea of the
glute ham roller which is brilliant now
all the companies are knocking them off
feel like sorex has gotten knocked off
so much in their time they've been so
Innovative I'm a huge fan of sorex my
only problem with this is is when you do
it you'll start moving your you get all
squirly so I made this track and I had
my dad cuz I don't know how to weld I
had my dad I went to Home Depot bought
some angled iron had my dad weld it
together and now you just use this track
and you stay symmetrical it's such an
awesome hamstring um device and the
stronger you get you can do them single
leg or you can Elevate yourself and pull
yourself up a ramp which makes it brutal
I can't do them but my girls can my
girls can even do single leg elevated
which is brutal but if you have like a
garage gym and you want to do like more
leg curl variations this is such an
awesome way we also do different types
of lunges and like kneeling rolling
lunges um it's very versatile now we've
got the seated leg curl this is Life
Fitness I I very much like this model
lets you move through a big range of
motion we also have the Paramount Ling
leg curl I love it it's a great Ling leg
curl a lot of these are old school
models I love old school equipment now
we have the BC strength 45° hyper I
spent 2 years prototyping this here's
what I love about the BC strength this
is less expensive to ship because we
made it in two parts so it's not one one
giant unit but you save money on
shipping that way you order a BC
strength 45 hyper you'll get it within
10 days but usually within like five
business days cuz we ship it the next
day okay I told you earlier I have two
clients here that are 4 10 they use this
with ease I think I had a 49 uh girl use
it once so this fits like 49 4 10
5-footers are always frustrated with
glute training they can't use most back
extensions they can use the BC strength
now it also telescopes way up and you
could you know I use eight okay this is
where I use it hole eight but it goes to
Hole 10 so I'm
6'4 yeah here's hole 10 as you can see
so I could be a lot taller I think I
could have at least like a 6ot pan
person use this and they'd be fine here
but what's so cool about this is that
these bands the way we made these guys
so conducive to bands so I I first did
this with my hip Thruster device the
reason I made a hip thrust station is so
you could do band hip thrust including
bar plus band and I used to put the pegs
straight out like this and the bands
would kind of wrap around it like
picture of this being straight out
they'd go at an angle and it would kind
of warp the Bands a little bit so then I
started making the T handle for the hip
Thruster and I made the little te handle
for the band attachment well I first
made this in a te and then I realized if
I angle these down it prevents them from
slipping out so this is so nice for
banded 45° hypers we just keep the bands
there those little things that clients
love so if you're looking for a 45°
hyper in my opinion BC strength is by
far the best however now they're making
selectorized and plate loaded devices
booty Builder glute Builder which I will
show you in a second I do want to show
the BC strength blocks and t-bell
station you can do squats off this you
can do stiff like deis I will tell you
the squats when you do squats with this
they're so glute dominant you can just
sit back you can do such glute dominant
squats but you can also do you know
stiff leg deadlifts Romanian deadlifts
it's for people who don't tolerate
squats and Deads well a lot of times if
you Center the loading and Let It Go in
between their legs they tolerate it so
much better I can't say enough about
this station I wish every gym had these
these get used all the time okay moving
on we got the loaded 45° hyper stations
so first we have booty Builder this has
band attachments it's actually a really
small footprint it lets you go really
deep I love this thing my ladies love it
you could also do Kickbacks off of it if
you wanted you can do Kickbacks but if
you're a gym owner trust me you buy this
the women will love it the men like it
too cuz it's annoying like me I can do a
100 lb dumbbell for 30 reps I've done
150 lb dumbbell for 22 reps it's
annoying dragging weight around so this
makes it so much more convenient the
only problem is I'm freakishly strong at
these I have done the stack plus bands
for 22 reps okay that's my PR if I
wanted to use like loading for 10 rep
max then I have to use the glute Builder
plate loaded one now what's better the
booty Builder or the glute Builder okay
what I like about booty Builder is it's
selectorized it's so convenient you just
pop the weight in done with glute
Builder you got to load it so nine
plates is 360 I just say the apparatus
weighs 45 yeah I've done 440 lb for 10
reps I am freakishly strong at this so
if you're freakishly strong at 45°
hypers you're fine with this there's
band pegs here to make the lockout
harder it also comes with rack with
storage with plate storage but the
reason why my women love this machine is
because you can put your legs here and
do straight leg 45° hypers but you can
also bend your knees here and do bent
leg 45° hypers it's funny when I first
applied for my patent in 2006 for the
scorcher for the hip Thruster I designed
a bent leg 45 hyper a bent leg reverse
hyper model literally 19 years later and
it's finally coming to fruition and it's
so nice to see my friend uro be the one
that made it because he's so Innovative
and then hack on is my friend he's the
owner of bootybuilder I feel with hack
on and Arturo they're just renovating
glute training around the world I hope
that BC strength can join in on the mix
and have more plate loaded devices too
it's just hard to do it's taking us time
we got the Hammer Strength now it's
funny this is called the the groundbased
squat lunge we don't do squats or lunges
off of here we do deadlifts Romanian
deadlifts stiff leg deadlifts single leg
deadlifts this is so nice for balance
issues because yeah let's say you have
stability issues if you load up the
plates here it's easier at the top
hardest at the bottom see this one stays
consistent so I really want to load the
stretch position I can come down you
know boom that is so much loading on
this hamstring as I come up so I love
this machine for stable single leg
Romanian deadlift and stiff leg deadlift
variations but a lot of my girls will do
double leg off here this is the glute
Builder I don't know what it's called
the deadlift or split squat machine but
yeah you can do loaded split squats you
can do deadlifts of it we don't use this
that much just because we have the pit
shark and we have the Hammer Strength
this is the Rogue reverse hyper I have
the classic reverse hyper from Westside
in my San Diego gym I've had that since
2003 this unit's a little bit smaller
thing about the reverse hyper I love
them in theory but it's like Cabell
swings we can use the t-bell and do
heavy Swings with them but they're just
so so much cardiovascular demand you
know you got to get it going and then
you yeah they're better for High Reps
sometimes we put extra cushion here
because it takes a lot out of you but
the reverse hyper is legendary Louis
Simmons made it popular we don't use it
that much though in fact in San Diego
it's always the workstation we have the
PLO box here and people work off of it
and it's always where people set their
purses and stuff in San Diego here I put
it away from the door but yeah everyone
hangs their stuff off it anyway what I
like about this is you can climb
underneath and do pendulum quadraped hip
extension you can do donkey kicks if you
kneel down underneath it I start start
doing those because I didn't have a
kickback machine in my first gym called
lifts in 2006 I was doing that and this
was a staple everyone did pendulum
quadruped donkey kicks or or quadruped
hip extensions either bent leg or knees
extending that was a staple in my first
gym but you can do this one leg at a
time or two legs at a time this is a
great exercise if you have a gluten
balance just do the one leg cuz it
doesn't work as much hamstring and
adductor it's mostly all glute all right
now I've got the Hammer Strength
kneeling leg curl this is my favorite
kneeling leg curl machine I like it cuz
I'm tall and I can kind of bend over as
I do it you know I can do these bent
over where if you're short you're be
more upright I can make it a little bit
more like a seated leg curl if I wanted
anyway this is such a good device I love
it it's leite FTS glute ham Rays I like
this Elite FTS unit because it goes It
goes tall here a lot of the ones I saw
in like CrossFit Gyms this stays low and
it's so much easier so you want to make
it hard put this up high it's markedly
higher but we don't do as many glute ham
raises as I used to back in the day
because we do more Nordic ham curls this
here is the BC strength Nordic I
designed this after the SX model see
rogu start making a flat grounded model
and SX used to make those like this and
I'm like I missed the SX model it was
better you want it to be elevated so I
made it a little bit smaller than Sor
X's Model A little bit lighter for
shipping but yeah you want it up high
because if you try to stay in full hip
extension like this okay then a lot of
times people sink like a a ship they
just you stay up the whole time they get
to about here halfway down and they sink
but if you let people lean a little bit
just a little bit and then they keep
that lean they can lower it under
control and then see here I can still
get full knee extension and then come
back up so I really like the elevated
models more and then finally we've got
the pit shark this is legendary this is
the best belt squat in my opinion I've
used them all I hear all these coaches
and trainers and people saying that they
made a better belt squat machine and I
don't agree I think pit shark made the
best ever shout out to them I have one
of these in San Diego I feel like you
actually see more deadlifts off of this
than than belt squats now and I think I
had a lot to do with that cuz I've
always had a c to row handle on here
because Westside was doing that back in
the day they were doing belt squats but
they also did deadlifts with the handle
so I started doing that with my glute
squads and yeah we do more deadlift
variations than belt squats but I love
them for belt squats too it's such a
classic machine now I'm going to show
you the free weight room we've got the
Rogue sled this makes it super
convenient cuz you can push it one way
throw these in push it the other way got
my my dumbbell rack these go up to
hundreds but I got 150s right here which
I use for 45° hypers and if I wrist
straps I do one on rose with them I've
also got 110 and 115s all right so here
we've got our glute benches we got the
Rogue sled we got the dumbbell rack here
we got this dip station this is Body
Solid I love it sometimes it's a little
wobbly but it's such a Nifty dip station
we've got the BC strength parallel bars
The laar Equalizer was the first one of
these so ingenious we started making it
I just made sure it was extra tall cuz
you don't want to touch down on these
all right seated shoulder press bench
we've got sturdy bench we've got this
inclinable bench now here we've got a
bunch of specialty bars this's an old
school rackable cambird bar I even shave
these off right here so it doesn't rub I
use this all the time for low bar cuz it
doesn't hurt my arms low bar sometimes
irritates my arms we've got the safety
squat bar we've got this football or
swiss bar or whatever you call it
neutral grip bar we've got the hex bar
easy bar and then the Buffalo bar now
here is the BC strength glute rack now
it's not all put together but this is my
favorite rack and here's why look at all
these numbers look at the detail you
have numbers all the way up to whole 34
so you can learn your hole you got this
guy that fits in right here if you want
and with this you can do hi thrust band
hip thrust single leg hip thrust you got
two different bar holders within it and
high quality look at that strength so
quality these are all numbered too so
you can do a lot of things off this if I
just had a garage gym I would get the
glute rack and buy all the accessories
with it I have my chains here different
like land mine and different accessories
here I have the incline press here I
have the Rogue bench press station I
love it I bought this off of World Gym
Scottdale in I think it was it was like
early 2000 I bought this off of them
this thing's so old all right here's
where I store my camera equipment and
stuff here I've got a welding station
for my prototyping but this is bathroom
four and
five this is the bathroom that my glut
Squad takes pictures in because of this
the lighting is unbelievable so they
always take their selfies in here I
really like these signs though take a
deep breath and remember who the fu you
are never be ordinary never be mediocre
be a wolf it be a lion take those set
goals smash them destroy them be a
strong version of you show people who
the you are never apologize for being
awesome you go mother now in this room I
have my two Idols my two Heroes my
number one alltime hero is Arnold this
is his quote you can have results or
excuses not both that's one of Arnold's
famous quotes and then I have the rock
here and the rock is saying always be
the hardest worker in the room and I
love that such Legend so cool to me to
have murals of my two Heroes I just
bought this this is a lad raise station
Revolt makes it kind of cool you could
say why not just use dumbbells but I
like equipment now we have the Life
Fitness lot raise machine I've gotten so
strong at this can put on 200 lb with
these two five so 210 I've done 12 reps
my shoulders have grown in the last uh
year I also have this preacher curl
Machine by Precor and I love it it's so
comfortable I will say it doesn't work
the stretch position as much it's kind
of harder up here but my biceps got the
biggest they've ever been just because I
was able to do more volume it just
allows me to do more volume of curls
okay now I've got different marker
boards skeleton um yeah different stuff
for filming podcast all the different
ring lights and lights for filming oh
here's a a desk and a backdrop for some
of my YouTube videos looks like a loft
but it's actually just a backdrop okay
now I have the upper body room the
seated row machine this is a plate
loaded lap pull down machine here we've
got our chest supported row here we've
got the Hammer Strength decline press in
Las Vegas I have the Hammer Strength
super incline press and I like that more
than here I wish I had them both here
I've got a treadmill and a stair Master
love having these the ladies love it
these get used all the time okay I've
got a Life Fitness lap pull down machine
in all my gyms I've got this mag grips
my favorite cuz I like chinups more than
pull downs but I also have all the
different pull down attachments here
I've got plate loaded shoulder press
I've got a pec deck and reverse pec deck
this is our prototyping area so right
now I'm trying to experiment with the BC
strength Thruster Pro let's see if I can
make it kind of like where you can load
up the top position versus the bottom
position more and kind of hard to figure
out but yeah we're always trying to make
new pieces and experiment I just got
this big fridge so I'm going to be
putting more food and stuff in here but
yeah here we've got mini fridge
microwave water and here's our storage
area this is our bean bag from Love Sack
everyone loves this little blanket
sometimes the girls will take naps here
when they're trying like filming content
and stuff and then we have a plate
loaded upper chest machine and another
plate loaded shoulder press machine the
last thing I want to say about G lab I
wanted to have super long asurf track
down the middle in case you wanted to
push the sled in case you wanted to do
walking lunges in case you want to do
lateral band walks or Farmers walks or
athletic stuff how cool would that be
and I love it when I got this place it
had walls separating everything so I
opened up the walls and made it six Bays
my landlord loves me he wants me to rent
the other unit too so I may I may get
the fourth room and have eight Bays but
I kind of love it as is the booty buett
neon sign the glute lab neon sign all
the different black the dark colors all
the lighting I spent 300 Grand on all
the renovations okay and that's not
including the equipment I made the
bathrooms way better I just made
everything so much better in here from
lighting to painting to floors and
mirrors and murals and all that when I
got this place it was just cement and
dust so I'm very proud of how this
looked and how it's designed but I just
want to throw out there how expensive it
was because yeah a lot of people want
their own glute lab a lot of people wish
I franchise they say Brett I want to I
want to build a glute lab well I would
estimate all this equipment would be at
least like a couple hundred grand and
the reen Renovations were a few hundred
grand so yeah it'd be half a million if
you wanted something like this so I
believe each room is 1,500 square ft so
this is like 4500 square ft I have the
option of making it 6,000 squ ft but
right now I have all the bathrooms I
need what would be cool is to have like
a soundproof podcasting room and like my
YouTube setup there permanently with all
the lights there so I just sit down and
record maybe that's for down the road
I'm kind of out of room if I had to get
more equipment I would love to have a
couple more quad machines in here here
feel like I have every glute machine I
want maybe I would want the prime
Kickback it looks cool I've just never
used it but I've worked the last almost
20 years to be able to afford this and
live this lifestyle I hope this
motivates a lot of you youngsters
watching this because yeah if you would
have told me 20 years ago you're going
to have your own gym I don't even charge
my members I haven't made an official
gym yet I just let select people train
here for free I got a squad I quit
taking on new people and that's what I
do for San Diego as well cuz I make
money online through Booty by Brett
through BC strength and so this is just
fun for me I come to the gym I can work
out myself I can film social media
content but I also train all these
people and they love me I train them for
free so they all love me and they're
never annoyed at me for wearing Jorts
and flipflops and tank tops and not
being organized and showing up late if I
was charging everyone for training
they'd definitely be annoyed so I've
showed you glute lab 4 LL now let's
check out my Florida home so I've showed
you the gym now I want to show you my
house so if you recall from my cribs in
Las Vegas several years ago I had a
Toyota Tacoma it was a really shitty one
now I have a new Toyota Tacoma I got one
with the sunroof the moon roof um yeah I
think it was like 70 grand but this is
by far the nicest car I've ever had I
just don't care about cars I thought
about getting a G wagon I thought about
getting like the Lamborghini SUV but I
just don't care about cars um but yeah
come
inside come come beautiful house on the
water I will take you on a tour but the
most important the coolest thing about
this house is the view because I live
right on the
water and you can see we have yeah
amazing pool jacuzzi grass palm trees
right on the water and it's January I
went swimming today I 2 hours you know
pacing across the deck in the sun
getting a tan in January in the middle
of winter
Priceless so I still have Skelly I got
the gargoyle these are same ones I have
in Las Vegas the little mini fridge
stored with Canada Dry Ginger Ale
turning a lot of people on to them zero
zero calorie this is like alcohol for
parties I don't really drink speaker for
parties this is the same couch I have in
all of my places I've got this same
couch my San Diego home my Las Vegas
home it's a love set couch these are my
favorite this fits a lot of people also
have this same TV everywhere it's a Sony
Bravia with a Sono sound system so your
couch and your TV setup in my opinion
are very very important because if you
love being at home your home makes you
feel good and you love watching TV
kicking on the couch it actually saves
you money throughout the year when
you're at home you're not spending come
downstairs here we have guest room
number one incredible view this actually
has the most ofle bed looks can be
deceiving this bed is priceless okay
then we have bathroom here and a little
room down here little
guy so that's the downstairs this is
kind of where I film things you might
recognize this area from some of my
YouTube videos or from some of my
Instagram videos filming region here we
have guest bedroom number three still
with a nice view huge
closet
bathroom okay now we have the kitchen
here very open I always show my what we
got here got lots of candy cereal nuts
dried fruit same as I always have we got
yogurts cheese peanut butter bars Pizza
leftovers milk yeah sure you were
expecting healthier
but that's how I get the gains here okay
now this here is the relaxation room
okay here's another Pantry snacks okay
good vibes only we've got a massage
table we have a a dry sauna if you
recall in my Vegas house I have a steam
room this is what gets used the most
because this is a red light infrared
sauna so you turn this on these are all
the red lights this gets up to like
170° for red light that's crazy but I
also have this guy and this here is red
infrared and blue light so we'll aim
this there too so you get it from all
over you get infrared light you get red
light you get blue light and you can
hook up to Bluetooth speakers in here
you can turn on lights you can turn on
LED lights we'll have the speakers going
you can play relaxation music you can
play party music now this is also a dry
son if you wanted it to be but we just
use it for the red light also if you
wanted lights up here and have these
little guys this thing's amazing all
right washer and dryer room got another
bathroom the one I use the most and
finally let's go
upstairs we have guest bedroom number
four and finally this is my bedroom the
master so I'll show you the bathroom
first we've got really nice bathtub
we've got dual shower heads and we have
the bedet cannot recommend these enough
why doesn't America Embrace b day don't
get it okay now as for my closet I just
want to show you I I do have a million
pairs of Jorts so many Jorts is not even
all of them and my
bedroom this fortunately there's not
much magic happening here but you could
imagine the view another mini fridge
over there sound machines and you've got
this amazing view they're building next
door so that looks a little weird but
yeah this my view here
so I've shown you my gym I've shown you
my house now I politely ask you get the
out